Knolls Action Project; Records apap105
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1975-1994; 6; 3.4 cubic ft.
  - KAPL: Windsor Site, 1980 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 17)
    Includes GAO's Analysis of Alleged Health and Safety Violations at the Navy's Nuclear Power Training Unit at Windsor, Connecticut.
  - Labor, 1989; 1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 18)
    Clippings on defense industry workers. Articles on labor disputes (1989) and diversification (1992).
  - Malta Test Station, 1986 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Military Contractors, 1980-1981; 1985-1987; 1989 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 20)
    Clippings, information sheets, and a report prepared by the American Friends Service Committee and the Central New York Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign Onondaga County's place in the nuclear arms race: Anti-submarine warfare.
  - Military Toxics, 1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 21)
    Article from Seattle Times.
  - Miscellaneous Handwritten Notes, [Undated] (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 22)
    Notes regarding status of FOI requests, contamination, National Resources Defense Council (NRDC), and other miscellaneous subject areas.
  - Naval Reactor Program (NRP): Activist Summit, 1993 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 23)
    Proposed agenda for activist meeting on Naval Reactor Program issues.
  - NRP: INEL Facilities, 1984; 1988-1993 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 24)
    See oversize box for The Waste Paper.
  - NRP: Overview, 1982; 1988; 1990-1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - "Nuclear Culture: Rituals of Renewal Among Nuclear Weapons Scientists", 1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 26)
    Paper presented at the American Association for the Advancement of Science meetings.
  - Nuclear Facilities NYS (commercial), 1991-1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Nuclear Power, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Nuclear Ships/Weapons Inventory, 1987-1994 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 29)
    Articles and reports on the nuclear arms race at sea.
  - Nuclear Testing Moratorium, 1984-1993 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 30)
    Articles, newsletters and reports.
  - ONR: Hanford Decommissioning Site, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 31)
    Disposal of decommissioned, defueled Naval Submarine Reactor Plants.
  - OSHA, 1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 32)
    Information on the Occupational Safety and Health Administration's finding that DOE's health and safety programs are insufficient.
  - Peace Pole, 1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Racism/Organizing Issues, 1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 34)
    Information sheet "Taking Action Against Racism and Violence" by the War Resisters League.
  - Radiation Dangers, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 35)
    Fact sheets.
  - Radiation Studies, 1978-1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 36)
    Articles, newsletters, fact sheets and reports.
    See oversize box for The Day, Feb. 4, 1990, Nuclear Power and its Alternatives, National Association of Radiation Survivors.
  - Radiation Victims, 1986; 1991 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 37)
    Articles; also information from the National Committee for Radiation Victims on the Radiation Victims Rights Project.
  - Radioactive Waste, 1979; 1982-1985; 1991-1992 (Box 1 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 38)
    Clippings. Also, 1979 memorandum from DOE Division of Security on reporting demonstrations.
    See oversize box for The Waste Paper, published by the Sierra Club.
  - Radioactive Waste, 1991-1992; 1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Radioactive Waste/Ballston Spa School Board, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Radioactive Waste: Low-level (West Valley), 1983-1985; 1987-1989; 1991; 1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 3)
    Contains reports and fact sheets from both consumer organizations and government agencies.
  - Radiological Monitoring (Citizens), 1990-1991; 1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Royal Navy: Nuclear Emergency Planning, 1990-1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 5)
    Contains reports by Greenpeace, and William Peden of the Nuclear Transport Information Group on the planning for nuclear naval accidents in specific areas of Great Britain.
  - SSN: Centurion Class Submarine, 1988-1992 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - SSN-21 Press Coverage, 1988-1992; 1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 7)
    Primarily clippings on the Seawolf Class Submarine.
  - SSN-21: Seawolf Class Submarine Overview, 1987; 1989-1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Seawolf Advance Fleet Reactor (AFR), 1992; 1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 9)
    Correspondence related to the construction and testing at Kesselring of the prototype nuclear reactor for the Seawolf.
  - Seismic Activity: New York State, ca. 1989 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Speech - Suzanne Massie, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 11)
    Speech delivered to the Committee for National Security, Washington D.C.
  - Transport, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 12)
    Information related to the transport of nuclear waste.
  - Trident, 1981-1990 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 13)
    Articles, leaflets and clippings related to the Trident Submarine.
    See oversize box for poster: Stop the D-5 (Trident II) Missile.
  - U.S. Nuclear Weapons Deployments, 1992 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 14)
    "Taking Stock: U.S. nuclear deployments at the end of the cold war", Greenpeace/NRDC, August 1992.
  - U.S.N.: Charleston Naval Shipyard, 1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - U.S.N.: Mare Island Naval Shipyard, 1993 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 16)
    Includes two GAO reports.
  - U.S.N.: Naval Nuclear Incidents, 1989-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 17)
    Clippings, articles, information from Greenpeace.
    See oversize box for copy of The Day, (1990).
  - U.S.N.: Norfolk Naval Shipyard, 1991; 1993-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 18)
    Clippings and a GAO report.
  - U.S.N.: Pearl Harbor Naval Shipyard, 1991-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 19)
    Includes copies of Environment Hawaii (1991-1993).
  - U.S.N.: Portsmouth Naval Shipyard, 1981; 1988; 1993-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 20)
    Primarily clippings.
  - U.S.N.: Puget Sound Naval Shipyard, 1979; 1992-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 21)
    Includes reports from GAO and SEARCH, a public interest project of The Tides Foundation.
  - U.S.N.: Submarine Strategy, 1989-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 22)
    Includes reports from the Natural Resources Defense Council and the U.S. Naval Institute.
  - USSR/CIS: Naval Nuclear Incidents, 1991-1994 (Box 2 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 23)
    Much of the information prepared by Greenpeace.
  - AFR - Draft Environmental Assessment and Testimony, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 1)
    "Proposed Finding of No Significant Impact (FONSI)" based on the "Environmental Assessment: Installation and operation of the AFR prototype in the S8G prototype plant located at the KAPL Kesselring Site", and NRDC/KAP comments.
  - AFR: Public Testimony and Comments on Environmental Assessment, 1990 December 05 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - AFR - NNP Testimony Handouts, 1990 December 05 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - AFR - NRDC Lawsuit - Current Draft, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - AFR - NRDC Lawsuit - Originals, 1990-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - AFR - NRDC Lawsuit - Press Releases, 1990 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - AFR - NRDC Lawsuit - Previous Drafts, 1990-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Babcock and Wilcox: Naval Nuclear Fuel Facility, [Undated] (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Base Closures/Realignment, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 9)
    GAO report Military Bases: Analysis of DOD's recommendations and selection process for closures and realignments.
  - Committee Nuclear Power Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 10)
    Testimonies given to the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Science, Space and Technology (1993).
  - Comprehensive Test Ban, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Conversion Issues, 1989-1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Defense Industrial Base Issues, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 13)
    Briefing Book on the Military-Industrial Complex published by Council for a Livable World Education Fund, and GAO report Defense Industrial Base: An overview of an emerging issue.
  - Dose Reconstruction Studies, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 14)
    The Savannah River Site Dose Reconstruction Project.
  - Dry Cask Storage Information, ca. 1989 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 15)
    Information packet from the Nuclear Information and Resource Service (NIRS).
  - ELF (Trident Communications), 1978-1979; 1982; 1984; 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 16)
    Correspondence, newsletters, reports regarding Project ELF (Extremely Low Frequency), a submarine communications facility that transmits Extremely Low Frequency electromagnetic radiation.
  - FOIA Document Index, 1989-1991; 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - FOIA Requests: Guidelines, 1988-1990 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - FOIA Requests: NYS Government, 1991-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 19)
    Correspondence related to the use of the Ballston Spa sail siding for the transport of radioactive materials.
  - F.O.N.S.I., 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 20)
    Finding of No Significant Impact based on the "Environmental Assessment: Installation and operation of the AFR prototype in the S8G prototype plant located at the KAPL Kesselring Site".
  - General Electric, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 21)
    Articles on GE boycott; GE and PCBs.
  - Gidon-Lawsuit/related correspondence, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Idaho vs. DOE Congressional Exemption, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 23)
    Contains testimony before the Senate Armed Services Committee on the shipment of spent nuclear fuel from US Navy ships and submarines to the Idaho Natl. Engineering Laboratory (July 28, 1993).
  - Idaho and Spent Nuclear Fuel Disposal, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Idaho and Spent Nuclear Fuel Lawsuits, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 25)
    Legal documents.
  - KAPL: Hazardous Waste Contingency Plan, 1990 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 26)
    Information from DOE.
  - KAPL/DOE: Dennis Dougherty Letter, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 27)
    Letter to Admiral Watkins, Secretary DOE regarding the danger of the use of a new pressure vessel head with an old pressure vessel.
  - KAPL/DOE: Scheib/Pax Christi Letter, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 28)
    Letter to Vice-President Gore suggesting ways to reduce waste in government.
  - Labor/Environmental Issues, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Low-Level Radioactive Waste, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 30)
    NIRS fact sheet.
  - MRS: Monitored Retrievable Storage, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 31)
    Memorandum from Arjun Makhijani, Institute for Energy and Environmental Research.
  - Martin Marietta, 1992-1994 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Military Toxic Wastes, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - N.L. Industries, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - NNP: Thresher/Scorpion Sinkings, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 35)
    Included copies (Undated) of two previously confidential "Findings of Fact" which were the results of the inquiries into the incidents.
  - NRDC/KAP Letter: DOE - Correspondence related to AFR, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - New York State: Government Oversite, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 37)
    Includes DEC Directory, Guide and Who's Who fact sheet on managing hazardous substances.
  - New York State: Low-Level Radioactive Waste Transportation Report, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - New York State Emergency Response Plan, 1990-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Nuclear Issues: USSR/C.I.S., 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Nuclear Reactors: Yankee Rowe, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - ONR (Office of Naval Research): FY 1988 Budgets, 1987 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - ONR: FY 1989 Budgets, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - ONR: FY 1990-1991 Budgets, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - ONR: FY 1992 Budget (NRP), 1991-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - ONR: FY 1993 Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Offsite Fuel Policy - Environmental Assessment, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Plowshares Actions, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Plutonium Issues, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Reactor Dismantlement, 1990-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 50)
    Includes clippings, and a copy of Decommissioning of Nuclear Facilities: An analysis of the variability of decommissioning cost estimates. This is a publication of the International Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.
  - Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA)/Toxics at KAPL Sites, 1990-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - S8G Prototype Environmental Statement, 1972 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - SP-100: Space - Based Reactor, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 53)
    GAO Report Space Nuclear Propulsion: History, cost, and status of programs.
  - Secrecy in Government, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 54)
    Two copies of Secrecy & Government Bulletin, publication of the Federation of American Scientists.
  - Site Specific Advisory Boards/Keystone, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Uranium Enrichment Issues, [Undated] (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 56)
    Uranium enrichment fact sheet prepared by the National Taxpayers Union.
  - Weapons Cuts, 1991-1992 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 58)
    The Other Westinghouse: Weapons and waste, a publication by Jonathan Pressler and the River City Nonviolent Resistance Campaign.
  - Whistleblower Issues, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 59)
    GAO Report Whistleblower Protection: Agencies' implementation of the whistleblower statutes has been mixed.
  - GE: Boycott, 1982-1988; 1991 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 1)
    See oversize box for two bumper stickers and button.
  - GE: Community Relations, Miscellaneous, 1984-1987 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - GE: Environmental, Energy Safety, 1979; 1984-1987; 1991-1992 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - GE: Jobs, 1980-1981; 1984-1987 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - GE: Personnel, 1982; 1984-1988 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - GE: Profits, Taxes, Business Deals, 1982-1987 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - GE: Scandals, 1985-1987 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - GE: Stockholders Alliance, 1980; 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - GE: Unions, Strikes, 1985-1987 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - General Electric Company, 1979-1988 (Box 4 (6-Miscellaneous Subject Files), Folder 10)
- Military Resistance and Nuclear Disarmament, 1965-1993; 7; 5.0 cubic ft.
  Billy Aul donated much of the material in this series. It contains primarily leaflets, flyers and handouts from grassroots organizations promoting draft resistance and conscientious objection, economic conversion, and military tax resistance. As a draft counselor, Ms. Aul helped conscientious objectors obtain discharge from military service. There are several cases documented in Box 1. Some of these folders contain personal information and access is restricted. Please consult the Curator of Manuscripts for access. The collection contains papers from the Military Tax Resistance and Alternative Fund (MTRAF). According to the Statement of Purpose: The MTRAF represents conscientious objectors who refuse to support the military with their tax dollars. Alternatively, we wish to donate our combined, resisted tax monies to local, life-enriching activities (Box 4, Folder 15).
  - Actions/Dated Special Leaflets, 1980-1988 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee (AFSC), 1987-1988 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 2)
  - "Amerika"(film), 1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 3)
    Controversies resulting from airing of the film on television.
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists; Nuclear Times, 1985; 1987; 1991 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 4)
  - Capital District, 1979-1980; 1982-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 5)
    Information regarding defense spending in the Capital District area.
    Includes clippings, statements and correspondence from Congressman Sam Stratton.
  - Central America, 1984-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 6)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO), [Undated]; Flyers (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 7)
  - Children, 1983-1985; 1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 8)
    Includes leaflets, and testimony heard before House Select Committee on Children, Youth and Families (Rep. George Miller) holding hearing on Children's Fears of War (1983).
  - Citizens Energy Council, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 9)
    Bulletins.
    See oversize box for two copies of Nuclear Hazards (1981) and Energy News Digest (1983).
  - Civil Defense, 1982; 1984 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 10)
  - Coalition for a New Foreign and Military Policy, 1982-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 11)
  - Conscientious Objectors, 1980; 1984-1988 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 12)
  - Conscientious Objectors: 1. Active Case, ca. 1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 13)
  - Conscientious Objectors: 2. Case, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 14)
    Clippings, letters. Access to this folder is restricted. Please consult Curator of Manuscripts for access.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 3. Case, ca. 1990 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 15)
    Statement. Access to this folder is restricted. Please consult Curator of Manuscripts for access.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 4. Case, 1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 16)
    Letters to KAP.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 5. Case. Navy documents relating to case [RESTRICTED], 1984-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 17)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 6. Case, 1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 18)
    Flyers, clippings, hand-written notes. Access to this folder is restricted. Please consult Curator of Manuscripts for access.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 6. Case, 1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 19)
    Article, leaflet.
  - Conscientious Objectors: 7. Case, 1984-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 20)
    Statement, letters. Access to this folder is restricted. Please consult Curator of Manuscripts for access.
  - Conscientious Objectors: Letter from Saratoga Woman, [Undated] (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 21)
    Suggestions on influencing navy personnel at KNOLLS in West Milton.
  - Conscientious Objectors Information/Draft Counselor Training, 1980; 1985-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 22)
    Contains pamphlets from CCCO. See oversize box for bumperstickers.
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 23)
    Postcard to Carolyn Mow.
  - Cruise/Pershing II (European Reaction), 1981-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 24)
    Includes clippings, newsletters, statements documenting European grassroots opposition to the deployment of the Cruise and Pershing II missiles. See oversize box for copy of Campaign (News of CND activities), 1984 and copy of Rauhan Puolestal, 1984, English edition of Journal of Finnish Peace Committee. Also, a copy of In Amsterdam, Thinking about the Bomb, 1982 (Presented at an international public hearing sponsored by the World Council of Churches in Amsterdam, Nov 23-27, 1981); also poster "Work for Peace", and two copies of Sanity (voice of CND), 1984, 1985.
  - "The Day After" (film), 1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 25)
    Includes a viewers guide prepared by the Cultural Information Service.
  - Defense and Disarmament Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 26)
  - Defense Monitor, 1979-1980; 1983-1984; 1991 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 27)
    Newsletter of the Center for Defense Information.
  - Draft: Address Lists, 1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 28)
  - Draft: Aliens, 1984-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 29)
    Includes article from the National Lawyers Guild Military Law Task Force on "The obligation of undocumented workers to register under selective service law". See oversize box for copy of The Nonviolent Activist (1986).
  - Draft: Alternative Service, 1980; 1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 30)
  - Draft: Bail Fund, 1982 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 31)
  - Draft: Capital District Draft and Military Counselors, 1990-1991; clippings (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 32)
  - Draft: Civil Disobedience, 1980(?); 1982 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 33)
  - Draft: Complicity Statements, 1982 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 34)
    Statement of complicity with non-registrants.
  - Draft: Conscientious Objection, 1965; 1970-1971; 1980-1982; 1984-1985; 1990-1991 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 35)